Mohsin Haider

OVERVIEW

Creative and collaborative undergraduate with practical experience in design, prototyping, and machine operation. Demonstrated ability in communicating complex topics in a clear and effective way to a broad audience.

Programming: Python, Arduino, GitHub, Heroku, some experience with MATLAB

• Design Tools: Illustrator, Inkscape, Fusion 360

Prototyping: Laser Cutting, Waterjet, 3D Printing, CNC Milling, CAM

• Soft Skills: Communication, Problem Solving, Flexibility

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Engineering

Expected May 2022

Mechanical Engineering Intent

Pratt School of Engineering, Duke University, Durham, NC

GPA: 3.8 May 2018

High School Diploma

Raleigh Charter High School, Raleigh, NC

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- Calculus I, II, and III
- Fundamental Engineering Design
- Introductory Chemistry

- Linear Algebra
- Introductory Programming
- Introductory Biology

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Innovation Co-Lab Studio, Duke University

Durham, NC

Co-Lab Staff

Aug 2018 — Present

- Troubleshoot, repair, and maintain fleet of 75 3D printers in Duke University's Co-Lab Studio (Makerspace)
- Instruct students on how to operate 3D printers, water jet cutters, laser cutters, and CNC machines
- Advise wide variety of clients on best methods to utilize Co-Lab machines for their projects

Mathnasium

Raleigh, NC

Instructor

Sep 2017 — May 2018

- Taught two to four students at a time as they independently learned new topics using the Mathnasium Curriculum
- Provided homework help on a range of topics from elementary math to calculus

PROJECTS

Museum of Life and Science, Duke University (Freshman Engineering Project) Project: Automatic Skunk Feeder Durham, NC

Aug 2018 — Dec 2018

- Designed and constructed, with three other students, a feeder for small mammals in captive enclosures that dispenses food at random times in variable locations
- Initially created device for skunks but is being applied for use with chinchillas, possums, and lemurs at the museum

Discord Bot (Independent Side Project)

Aug 2017-Mar 2018

- Developed, using pre-existing python modules, a bot for chat application Discord that plays rock paper scissors, manipulates text inputs, and responds contextually to user input phrases
- Acquired knowledge of Python programming language, Windows command line, GitHub, and Heroku

VOLUNTEER AND LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Programming Club, Raleigh Charter High School

Raleigh, NC

President and Founder

Aug 2017— May 2018

- Developed and taught lessons on J, Python, and HTML to club members with varying experience levels
- Managed a scheduling program for an annual event and facilitated a school-wide transition from I to Python

IT Department, Raleigh Charter High School

Raleigh, NC

Tech Volunteer

Jun 2016— Aug 2016

- Spent 10 hours a week performing maintenance and administrative duties for the school's IT Department
- Replaced LCD screens on Chromebooks and systematically wiped over 40 hard drives